A Guide to the Sarah Pitt Collection, 1930-1936
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Sarah Pitt Collection, 1930-1939
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2005-018
0.25 cu. ft. 1 box
The collection contains papers relating to the Sarah Pitt Collection includes newsletters, newspaper articles, radio broadcasts, pageant script, and notebooks.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Sarah Pitt Collection was donated to the Digital Library and Archives (Special Collections) in February 2005.
Biographical Note
Sarah Pitt was an Extension Agent in Prince William County from 1930-1936.
Scope and Content
The Sarah Pitt Collection is composed of related records during her term as Extension Agent in Prince William County for the Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute and the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Extension Division.
A noteworthy component of this collection is 5 small notebooks in which Sarah Pitt recorded her thoughts, ideas, recipes and comments concerning 4-H and Extension activities. These notes are significant as they reveal farm-related activities during The Great Depression.
The collection also contains two radio broadcast scripts from the “National Farm and Home Hour”. In the 1930s and 1940s, the "National Farm and Home Hour" broadcast nationwide from Chicago and was sponsored by the American Farm Bureau.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title. The individual folders are arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute
Local Subjects:
University Archives
Contents List
- "Clover Leaves," July 20-24, 1936 (Box-folder 1-1)
- "Conservation." (Box-folder 1-2)
- Cooperative Extension, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 1-3)
- "Extension Service Review," June 1934 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Farm Women, 1936 (Box-folder 1-5)
- 4-H Clubs, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 1-6)
- 4-H Club Song Book, Virginia. (Box-folder 1-7)
- Hutcheson, John, R. – Two papers – "Virginia Agricultural Progress" and "The Why and the Whither of the AAA," 1934 (Box-folder 1-8)
- National Farm and Home Program, Radio Broadcast, 1939 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Newspaper Articles, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Pageant – "Ten Commandments of Agriculture," 6/18/30 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Sarah Pitt Notebooks, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Sarah Pitt Notebooks, n.d. (Box-folder 1-13)
- "Virginia 4-H Club Letter," October 1935, May 1939, August 1939 (Box-folder 1-14)